Adnan Birparić

Software Developer

Date and place of birth 14.04.1989. god. Banovići

Citizenship 1

Portfolio

rtfolio https://adcodffunnan.github.io/adnanbirparic/

E-mail adnan.birparic@gmail.com

GitHub account @adcodFfunnan

Address Sarajevo, Novi Grad, Džemala Bijedića 129

Phone number +387 61 178 397

ABOUT ME

I am an electrical engineer with great interest in computer programing. After several years of working as an electrical engineer, I decided to change my career and find a job in this field because it has always interested me the most. I am constantly improving my knowledge by researching popular software technologies and working on new projects to get a job as a Junior Software Developer. Below you will find my projects that showcase my skills and general background in developing software.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

MyPortfolio

GitHub Page: https://adcodffunnan.github.io/adnanbirparic/

This is my portfolio website built with React JS.

React JS Puzzle Game

GitHub Page: https://adcodffunnan.github.io/react_puzzle/

This is a puzzle game built using React JS. The game provides the ability to insert the image you want to play with, and it is possible to determine the level of difficulty. It can be played on desktops and mobile devices.

Music player (PHP & MySQL web app)

Web address: http://www.musicplayer.dx.am/

The app was created to help users dynamically create a playlist from youtube. The main advantage of this application is that after creating the main playlist from youtube, which exists every time the user logs in, the user can play any number of songs in a specific order.

The main playlist and the second playlist can be dynamically modified without pausing playback.

SnakeGame (JavaScript web game)

Web address: https://adnansites.000webhostapp.com/snakegame/

It is a classic snake game built with JavaScript and jQuery.

React JS Find Movie

GitHub Page: https://adcodffunnan.github.io/findmovie/

It is a movie search application created using the React JS and The Movie Database API. The app allows users to search for movies or TV shows and provide detailed descriptions with trailers.

Image transfer solution (Laravel PHP)

Demo video: https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1RLDxL7nJo

QfsVQi66VFyKbQeZi1RFMTp?usp = sharing

It is a multiple user application that allows users to transfer image files over the Internet. After loading the images, the application provides an access key which is used to access uploaded images. The list of uploaded images can be modified in terms of deleting or adding some images.

AutoCadPlot (Python and PyQT5 desktop app)

Demo video: https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1MzW3Z9In

WOrr-PlIKr09_cg14D_rotFk?usp=sharing

This app solves the problem of printing multiple drawings from AutoCAD. If we have several AutoCAD drawings ordered side-by-side, it takes time to print these drawings because each drawing has to be individually marked and printed. With the AutoCadPlot app, it can be done in seconds.

Voltage drop calculator (JavaScript web application)

Web address: https://adnansites.000webhostapp.com/voltagedrop/

The app calculates a voltage drop across each section, showing the calculation process itself.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2013

University of Tuzla

Qualification title

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering 240 ECTS

GPA

8.16

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

General Engineering d.o.o. Sarajevo

Jul 2017 - Apr 2020

Oct. 2018 - Aug. 2019 Field Automation Engineer

Automation of water supply system Gradiska

(The system integrates 30 water pump stations in one centralized SCADA system for control and monitoring.)

- Modification of existing technical solutions for the pump stations based on the actual situation on the site and new demands of the main engineer
- Programming and configuration VF drives based on the requirements of certain automated processes
- Testing and commissioning

Jul. 2017 - Oct. 2018 Design Engineer

- Preparation of the technical solution, design and calculation for transformer substations and power plants
- Technical evaluation of high voltage equipment, medium voltage switchgears and low voltage auxiliary equipment
- Design of operation diagrams, cable and wiring diagrams for LV control & protection panels

JP Elektroprivreda BiH d.d. - Sarajevo, Podružnica "Elektrodistribucija", Sarajevo

Jul. 2016 – Dec. 2016 Electrical Engineer

Apr. 2015 – Apr. 2016 (Internship)

SKILLS

Technical skills

- JavaScript, React JS
- HTML, CSS
- Java, Python and Qt
- PHP and MySQL

Personal skills

- Good communication skills and ability to work in team
- Commitment to work and willingness to learn
- Ability to solve problems using analytical and creative thinking

Native language

Bosnian

Other language

English (Upper – Intermediate)

Driving license

В

REFERENCES

Amir Becirhodzic

Lead SCADA and Automation Enigneer / Project Manager at General Engineering

Phone number: 061 / 323 563

E-mail: Amir.Becirhodzic@gene.ba

Almir Mahmutović

Head of Design Department at General Engineering

Phone number: 06

061 / 197 409

E-mail: Almir.Mahmutovic@gene.ba

Recommendations:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qtzL99TR511hVyYWymoTslNGYnAvGwXh/view?usp=sharing